欲将芳容比长夏
Should I compare thee to a summer's day?
而你比它更可爱(莎士比亚)
Thou art more lovely.
你觉得这好笑么?
You're laughing at that?
我还不能笑了么
I am allowed to laugh.
是他! 鲁迪2号!
It's him! It's Rudy 2!
退后点!
Stand back!
你是个医生?
Are you a doctor?
我是个电工
I'm an electrician.
有人被困在这里面了?
There's someone inside of there?
是啊
Yeah.
一个有超能力的人
It's someone with a power.
你好吗 朋友
All right, mate.
楼顶上那个是谁?
Who's that on top of the building?
或许是你呢
Maybe it's you.
万一咱们都变成超级英雄了呢?
What if we all become superheroes?
你干什么呢?      没...没事
What you doing?        Noth... Nothing.
见鬼 不好意思 我...还以为摸的是他脖子
Shit, I'm sorry, I just... I thought it was his neck.
莉亚?
Leah?
我能听见 我知道你在里面
I can hear you. I know you're in there.
莉亚!
Leah!
我知道那场风暴的时候你出了事
I know something happened to you in the storm.
我自己也出事了
Something happened to me, too.
我一直在参加这个小组...
I've been going to this group...
都是我们这样的人
It's for people like us.
(超能力互助小组)
你不用自己承受这一切
You don't have to go through it on your own.
我们可以一起去
We could go together.
我都好久没跟你一起了
I miss hanging out with you.
打给我
Call me.
(超能力互助小组)
(拨号)
(拨号中...)
莉亚?
Leah?
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
超能少年 第五季第5集
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：wren
校对：tpring
时间轴：Dot_Kuma
男人给矮人的忠告
From man-to-smaller-man,
你永远都过不了对杰茜的这份幼稚迷恋
you're never going to get over this childish infatuation with Jess
除非你找到一个特别崇拜你的妞
until you find a girl who looks up at you with little puppy-dog eyes
跟你说
and says the words,
"你的微型小鸡鸡吃起来好像橘子酱呀 费利"
"Your tiny little cock tastes like marmalade, Finlay."
你看看她 看起来不错
Now, look at her - she looks like a fun girl. Eh?
橘子酱小妞!
Lady Marmalade!
有人说 眼泪是最好的润滑剂
Some people say tears are the best form of lubricant.
没人会那么说
No-one says that.
噢...天啊      哦!
Oh...Jesus        Ow!
抱歉 我真的...
Sorry. I'm so...
润滑剂!
Lubricant!
那绝对是最好的润滑剂
It's the best form of lubricant.
比眼泪要好...
Better than tears...
橘子酱
...marmalade.
因为那个更润滑...
Because it's more lubricating...
快滚吧!
Just fuck off!
茶?
Tea?
希望能快点开始 我还要工作呢
Hope it starts soon - got work to do.
该死的文书工作 没完没了
Bloody paperwork - never stops, eh?
就是啊
I know.
你干嘛的?      监督官
What d'you do?        Probation worker.
噢 老天爷 对...对不起
Oh, my God, I'm...I'm so sorry.
噢 我的天
Oh, my God.
我就是想把饼干渣给你弄干净 我喷了你一脸
I was just going to clean the biscuit off. I kind of splattered ya.
好...好吧
O-OK.
我平常不会把茶和饼干喷在女人脸上的
I don't usually spit tea and biscuits in a girl's face.
除非人家自己要求 我不是说...
Unless she's asking for it. I'm not saying...
你要求我这么干...
you were asking for it...
不是的 真不是
No. No means no.
作为一个经常被人说不的家伙
And that's coming from a guy who gets told no a lot.
我是说 我不是那种死乞白赖找妞搭讪的人
I mean, it's not like I'm out there, forcing myself on girls.
我也不知道自己他妈的怎么回事
I don't know what the fuck is wrong with me.
真的很抱歉 反正你就别理我了
I'm really sorry. Just don't talk to me.
我...我就是个傻逼
I'm...I'm a twat.
我是莉亚
I'm Leah.
费恩
Finn.
我是费恩
I'm Finn.
"Don't Worry Baby" by the Beach Boys
* 这感觉一直在我内心萦绕 不知过了多久
# Well, it's been building up inside of me for oh, I don't know how long
* 我搞不懂为什么 总觉得哪里会出错 *
# I don't know why, but I keep thinking something's bound to go wrong...
彩色小糖豆啊! 你一直藏着呢吧 费利
Pick'n'mix! You've been holding out on me, Finlay.
小混球
Little bastard.
我知道你在干嘛
I know what you're doing.
等一下下!
Just a minute!
是关于杰茜 对吧?
This is about Jess, isn't it?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我说你把费恩带去互助小组 让他找妞搭讪
I'm talking about you taking Finn to the support group to hit on girls
你就不会因为喜欢杰茜而内疚了
so you don't feel so guilty about your feelings for Jess.
我反驳你的观点
Well, I refute that.
大概是吧..."反驳"是什么意思?
Or at least, I think I do. What does "refute" mean?
意思是你不承认某些事
It means you don't accept something.
对 那我就是反驳
Yeah, well, I refute that.
那我去跟费恩说
What if I was to tell Finn
你为什么急着给他找女朋友?
why you're so keen on him getting a girlfriend?
别 你不能 我真心喜欢杰茜啊...
Don't, you can't. I really like Jess...
反正你别搅和我的互助小组了 拜托
Just stay away from the support group, please.
行 不搅合!
Fine, I will!
我不管你那可笑的互助小组了 亲
I'll stay away from your ridiculous support group, pal.
哎 但我还是你大佬 亲
Oi, I'm still the boss of you, pal.
我反驳
I refute that.
哟 是么? 行
Oh, do you? Well,
等我学会了飞行 我要像老鹰一样翱翔天空
when I learn how to fly, I'm going to soar like a friggin' eagle.
我要从高空对准你的头拉一泡大屎
And I'm gonna take a massive shit on your head from a very great height.
那毛衣上的又不是你
It isn't you on the jumper.
你也说不准哦!
You don't know that!
织在毛衣上的东西容易分不清的
It's very difficult getting a good likeness in wool.
我不会让你毁了我们所有人的未来
I will not let you screw up the future for all of us.
擦 随便吧
Gah, whatever.
反驳了!
Refuted!
我反驳你 长官!
I refute you, sir!
你说我要不要过去帮他说几句好话?
Do you think I should go over and put a good word in for him?
你准备说什么?
What are you going to say?
我可以说说他那两个奇大的蛋
I could tell her about his strangely weighty balls.
就像... 毛茸茸的大苹果
They're like...hairy apples.
你是亚历克斯么?      对
Are you Alex?        Yeah.
有人说你可以帮我
I was told you can help me.
去掉我的超能力
With my power.
说说你的情况
What's the problem?
我会把东西都从里外翻
I turn things inside out.
嗯      听起来也不是坏事
Hm.        That doesn't seem that bad.
洗衣服的话就很方便
It's good for doing the laundry.
还有变性手术
And transgender surgery.
我把我的猫外翻了
I turned my cat inside out.
好吧...
OK...
我们不如去安静点的地方谈?
Why don't we go somewhere a bit quieter?
好
OK.
你的能力是什么
So what's your power?
什么?
What?
你的超能力
Your power.
之前你为什么去互助小组?      哦
Why were you at the support group?        Oh...
呃... 我听力超强
Er...I have super hearing.
那很酷啊
That's so cool.
什么?
What?
我说 "那很酷啊"
I said, "That's so cool."
我小声说的 因为你能...      对哦
I said it quietly, because you can...        Right.
但不是随时都行
It's not always on.
不然就吵死了        也对
It gets too loud.      OK.
那你呢? 你有什么能力?
So, what about you? What's your power?
我可以意念移动东西 不光是啤酒
I can move other stuff, too. Not just lager.
见鬼!        见鬼 真抱歉
Shit!      Shit, I'm sorry.
我...我该走了
I-I should go.
要我送你回家么?
Do you want me to walk you home?
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉 就让它自己晾干吧
Sorry. Just let it air dry.
不是那个 我是说裤子
Not it. The trousers.
让裤子自己晾干
Let them air dry.
我们走吧?
Shall we...?
嗨
..Hi.
你喜欢...苹果么?
Do you...like apples?
喜欢
yeah.
那你肯定会喜欢他的蛋
You are gonna love his balls.
我希望对你起作用了 向你的猫表示遗憾
Well, I hope everything works out for you. Sorry about your cat.
噢 无所谓
Oh, never mind.
我们刚刚...
We were just...
我们大概能猜到 不需要任何... 照片
We can probably guess, actually. We don't need...any photos...
视频
Videos.
哇... 祝你们今晚愉快
Well... Have a good night.
你也是 今晚已经很愉快了吧
Having a great night anyway, already.
亚历克斯
Alex.
酒保
From the bar.
管不住自己下半身 两秒都难 简直成病了
Can't keep it in his pants for more than two seconds. It's a sickness.
一种病
A disease.
我能留你的电话么?
Can I get your number?
当然
Sure, yeah.
我会打给你的      好
I'll call you.        OK.
今晚有人去酒吧么?
Is anyone going to the bar tonight?
我就在那上班啊      我又没问你
I work there.        I wasn't talking to you.
我跟你去呗      随便你
I'll go with you.        Whatever.
行啊 我也去喝一杯
Sure, I'll go for a drink.
好 噢... 见鬼 我去不了
Yeah. Oh, oh... Shit, I can't.
去不了了 我昨晚在互助小组认识了一个妞
No, I met this girl at the support group last night.
莉亚 我们真是...相当合得来
Leah. Yeah, we really, really connected.
后来又一起去喝酒了
Went out afterwards for a drink...
他们都看见了
They saw me.
所以...你这一顿假装叫大家去喝酒
So...this whole thing about going for a drink
就是为了跟我们说妞
is so you can tell us about this girl.
不是
No.
不是啊! 我只是...
No! I was...
我只是好奇你们今晚都有什么计划
I was just interested in what your plans were for tonight.
打扰了!
Excuse me!
心里在想事儿么?
Something on your mind?
在想你呢 想你
You're on my mind. You are.
你对我施了咒
You've cast a spell.
我吃不下 睡不着
I can't eat, I can't sleep
屎都拉不出
and I can't shit,
只有你
without that
脑袋里想的都是你!
popping into me head!
我真的... 不想打乱你的生活作息
Well, um, I hate to mess up your well-established routine
包括吃饭 睡觉 拉屎 所以...
of eating, sleeping and shitting, so...
收工后要不要碰面聊聊这事?
Do you want meet up later and talk about it?
嗯      好吧 约定了
Yeah.        OK. Well, it's a date.
擦 你这个小女巫
Grr, you're a witch.
美丽动人的小巫婆
You're a beautiful friggin' witch.
你知道吧
You know that?
"Pictures Of You" by the Cure
* 我一直在不断寻找
# I've been looking so long
* 关于你的那些照片
# At these pictures of you
* 我几乎相信了它们真的存在
# That I almost believe that they're real
* 失去你的照片 我只能失魂而活
# I've been living so long with my pictures of you
* 我几乎相信这些照片
# That I almost believe that the pictures
(莉亚 恋爱中)
* 就是我的灵魂的所在... *
# Are all I can feel... #
你好啊
Hiya.
嗨?
Hi?
你别怕 我...
Don't worry, I'm...
不会再把茶和饼干喷你脸上了
not going to spit tea and biscuits in your face.
除非你让我那么做
Unless you want me to?
抱歉 我认识你么?
Sorry, do I know you?
演得真好
Good one!
什么?
What?
噢 我明白了
Oh, I see.
你喜欢玩角色扮演
You like to play games.
那你可要小心点了
Well, you'd better watch yourself.
如果你想玩 要知道我可是
Because if you wanna play, then you're playing...
高手玩家
(..with a player.)
我完全不知道你在说什么
I've got no idea what you're talking about.
或你是谁
Or who you are.
你当然不知道了
Of course you don't.
游戏开始了
..Game on.
帮个忙好么
Do me a favour?
听候差遣
I'd love to.
给我滚他妈远点!
Stay the fuck away from me!
那么 你想谈谈咱们之间的事么?
So, do you want to talk about what's going on with us?
对的 想谈
Yeah, I do.
现在是这样 面对费利 就没有"我们"
Right, now, when it comes to Finlay, there is no "us".
说真的 我就直接装不认识你
Honestly, I'll just deny I even know you.
"杰茜? 是谁啊?
"Jess? Who's Jess?
是那个瘸腿的中国人吗?"
Is she that Chinese fella with a bit of a limp?"
那我们就不能诚实点么?
So we can't just be honest about it?
我们当然能啊! 当然能诚实!
Of course we can be honest! We can be honest about it.
我的小名就是"诚实"呀
That's my middle name
鲁迪·诚实·杰弗里·韦德
Rudy Honest Geoffrey Wade.
你先说
You go first.
我喜欢你      哇!
I like you.        Whoa!
这也真奇怪 因为你有时完全是个混球
Which is really weird, because you can be such a total dick.
嘿 喔! 我反驳
Hey, whoa! Well, I refute that.
这观点...
That's...
被我反驳了
That is refuted.
如果你要开始和我约会 我可不想遮遮掩掩
If you want to start seeing me, I'm not going to sneak around.
我们得告诉费恩
We have to tell Finn.
或者我们就不告诉他 就行啦
Or we could just not tell him. Bingo.
如果你...
If you...
想跟我在一起 我们就得告诉费恩
want to be with me, then we have to tell Finn.
我不确定啊 就没有一个折中的办法么...
I don't know, isn't there, like, a middle ground where we just...
折中到不用告诉他?
where we don't tell him?
就...
Just...
行 好吧 我去跟他说
Yeah, all right. I'll tell him.
男人与矮男的对话 我这就去跟他说
Man-to-smaller-man, I'm just going to have a word with him.
小菜一碟 噢!
It's not a problem. Oh!
呃!
Ugh!
这不是费利嘛!
Finlay's here!
费利来了啊
Finlay's here.
女人      在哪呢?!
Women.        Where?!
我是说
I'm saying.
前一分钟 你还...
One minute, you're...
喷人一脸饼干茶渣
spitting tea and biscuits in their face
人家还羞涩可爱的
and they're being all coy and shy
后一分钟 就一副根本不认识你的样子
and the next minute, they're acting like they don't even know you.
我受够了这些破事
I'm done with this bullshit.
哎 这是要往哪走? 过来
Wahey, where's he going? Come here.
你意思是 所有女人都受够了? 全体么?
You mean, like, done with all women? Everywhere?
天啊 伙计 女人多美丽啊 眉毛修得
Jesus, man - women are beautiful. They've got lovely little...
细细的很可爱 闻起来就像巧克力面包...
..shapely eyebrows, smell of pain au chocolat...
你这是说谁呢?
Who are you talking about?
什么?
What?
说我妈呢 浑身一股糕点味儿
Talking about me mum. She stinks of pastry.
天天就唠叨那些玩意
Absolutely hums of the stuff.
或许她荷尔蒙有问题 我也不知道
It's probably her hormones, I don't know.
好吧
Right.
杰茜
It's Jess.
嗷
Ah.
她是唯一适合我的女孩
She's the only girl for me.
听着 仅限咱俩之间
Now listen, between me and you,
你不用说别的 我就是...
don't say anything, I just...
我觉得杰茜有点太淫荡了
I think Jess might be a bit of a cunt.
喔 别那么说!      干嘛不能说?
Whoa, you can't say that!        Why not?
因为她是完美的
Because she's perfect.
没错 她是完美的 伙计 真的是
Yeah, she is perfect, mate. She is.
她就是完美本人
She's perfection.
呃
Eurgh!
噢 老天爷啊!
Oh, God's sake!
那你准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
你会告诉费恩你喜欢杰茜么?
Are you going to tell Finn about your feelings for Jess?
你他妈脑子进水了吧
Are you out of your friggin' mind?
我能做的只有一件事了
There is only one thing I can do.
"You Really Got Me" by The Kinks
* 女孩 你真让我疯狂
# Girl, you really got me going
* 你让我如此疯狂 我已失去了自己
# You got me so I don't know what I'm doing
* 对 你真的让我疯狂
# Yeah, you really got me now
* 你让我如此疯狂 我已夜不能寐... *
# You got me so I can't sleep at night... #
* 你让我如此疯狂 我已失去了自己
# ...So I don't know what I'm doing now
* 噢 耶
# Oh, yeah
* 你真让我疯狂 *
# You really got me now... #
费利?
Finlay?
看你的短信
(Check your messages.)
或许会发现一个...小礼物
Might find a little...present there.
是什么?      看吧 好好看看
What is it?        Check it out. Enjoy.
她这是在拉屎么?
Is she taking a shit?
她真是费了大劲在狂拉大号啊 伙计
She's taking the Mother Teresa of all shits, dude.
她脸都扭成一团了 怎么这样?
Her face is all contorted - what the fuck?
就说啊!
I know!
足够让你不再喜欢她了吧
It's enough to put you off her, isn't it?
呃 我不能再看了 噢 我的天!
Eurgh, I can't watch... Oh, my God!
这下你算是从幼稚迷恋中解脱了
Consider yourself cured of your childish infatuation.
你干嘛发一段杰茜拉屎的视频给我?
Why have you sent me a video of Jess taking a shit?
啊?      对 我也收到了
Eh?        Yeah, I got one of those, too.
我还以为是什么电子贺卡呢
I thought it was one of those e-greeting cards.
你们他妈开玩笑吧?
Are you fucking kidding?
糟了!
Shit!
早!
Morning!
早啊
Morning.
早...早上好 杰茜卡
Good...good morning, Jessica.
你他妈干什么呢? 我的手机!
What the fuck are you doing? That's my phone!
对 我知道 我刚刚解放了你
Yeah, I know, I've only gone and bloody liberated you,
让你不再为了发短信而受苦
freed you from the tyrannies of friggin' texting.
现在你自由了 脱下镣铐 摆脱它们
You're free now. Just take off your shackles, get rid of them,
扔进水里
throw it in there.
* 自...由... 纳尔逊·曼德拉
# Free-ee, Nelson Mandela
* 鞋太小不适合他的脚... *
# Shoes too small to fit his feet... #
他应该买其乐的鞋 他们有特宽的 对吧?
He should have gone to Clarks - they do a bit of a wider fit, don't they?
你得给我买个新手机
You're paying for a new phone.
为什么 你没有保险吗? 真见鬼了
What d'you mean, you don't have insurance? Bloody hell.
有的人会说你这样是很不负责任的
Well, some people might call that a bit irresponsible.
你懂我的意思吧
Know what I mean?
但我不觉得 我就觉得你可爱
Not me, I think it's adorable.
我就管这种叫可爱
I call it adorable.
我管这叫他妈的手机没了
I call it not having a fucking phone.
可爱!
Adorable!
操!
Fuck!
(拨号)
(拨号中...)
(莉亚来电)
你他妈这是干什么呢?
What the fuck are you doing?
你突然又认识我了?
So suddenly, you know me again?
哎 你得看看这个
Oi - you need to see this.
对 我知道      网上传开了
Yeah, I know.        It's all over the internet.
不是吧! 我操!
No! Fuck!
这下搬石头砸脚了 费利
The shit's hit the fan, Finlay.
石头是指他妈的万维网
By fan, I mean fuckin' World Wide Web.
咱们回头见      你去哪?
I'll see you later.        Where are you going?
去找莉亚
To see Leah.
我在互助小组认识的那个女孩
The girl I met at the support group.
真的吗? 那太好了
You are? That's brilliant.
快去吧 快点
Get gone. Go on.
知道么 那天晚上我看到他和她一起出了酒吧
You know, I saw him coming out of the bar with her the other night
而且她好像尿裤子了
and she looked like she pissed herself.
或是她下面太湿 然后就...
Or maybe her vagina had become so moist, it just...
从衣服里渗出来了?
..soaked through her clothing?
怎么可能发生过那种事?
And when has that ever happened?
2006年夏天 莉莎·金
Summer 2006, Lisa King.
水那叫一个多 就好像...
Her vagina so moist, it was like a...
春天里股股流淌的小溪
..gently bubbling brook on a beautiful spring day.
("Ever Fallen In Love?" - Buzzcocks)
* 失去你...而那更糟了... *
# ..And that's worse... #
* 你可曾爱过不该爱的人
# Ever fallen in love with someone Ever fallen in love
* 你可曾爱过不该爱的人 爱上了
# In love with someone Ever fallen in love, in love with someone
* 不该爱的人
# You shouldn't have fallen in love with?
* 我只是看不到未来
# I just can't see much of a future
* 除非我们懂得了责任
# Unless we find out what's to blame
* 真是可惜
# What a shame
* 噢 真是可惜
# Oh, what a shame
* 我们无法在一起
# And we can't be together
* 除非我们明白 我们彼此相像
# Until we realise that we are the same
* 你可曾爱过不该爱的人...
# Ever fallen in love with someone Ever fallen in love
嗨
Hi.
Hi...
你是谁?
Who are you?
我这是在哪?
Where am I?
你在我家
You're in my flat.
我在走廊里发现你晕倒了
I found you unconscious in the corridor.
我想你一定是出了意外
I think you must have been in an accident.
见鬼!
Shit!
我不知道发生了什么      你没事
I don't know what happened.        You're OK.
这是最重要的
That's the main thing.
我认识你么?
Do I know you?
不认识
No!
不过好奇怪 我也感觉我认识你
But it's weird, because I feel like I know you, too.
我...我该走了
I-I should go.
你不用走啊!
You don't have to!
喜欢的话可以留下来 想喝啤酒么?
Stay, if you like. Do you want a beer?
我...我得回去了 我在做社区服务
I... I've got to get back, I'm on community service.
留下吧 我们一起吃披萨
Stay. We'll have some pizza.
还是你喜欢中餐? 随便什么都行
D'you like Chinese food? Anything you want.
我... 我很想留下
I...I'd love to.
真的 我很愿意 但我还有事
Honestly, I would, but I've got things to do,
还得去捡垃圾
you know, like litter to pick up.
这里有我们需要的一切 我们哪儿都不用去
There's everything we need right here! We don't have to go anywhere.
好吧
..OK.
这挺有意思的 你知道么...
This has been fun, you know...
不管...这到底什么情况
whatever...this is.
咱们回头再见吧
I'll see you around.
别
Don't.
你玩够了吧 派对结束我要走了
You've had your fun, the party's over and I'm leaving.
滚开!      别!
Fuck off!        No!
这...?
Wh...?
你要不要告诉我这怎么回事?
D'you wanna tell me what's going on?
我们在一个虚拟世界里
We're in a virtual world.
我们咱俩都转换成了电子信号
I had us converted into electronic signals.
我们现在就是一长串1和0
We're just a long stream of ones and zeros.
现在有个问题
Here's a question.
你他妈干嘛要这么做?!
Why the fuck would you do that?!
我喜欢你
I like you.
你根本都不认识我!
You don't even know me!
是我
It's me.
莉亚
Leah.
那天晚上?
The other night?
在互助小组?
At the support group?
你喷了我一脸饼干渣
You spat biscuit in me face!
那个就是我
That was me.
我当时... 下载进了我朋友的身体
I was...downloaded into my friend's body.
好吧
OK.
我不想把话说得太重
I don't want to get heavy with you,
但我玩够你的电脑游戏了 行吗?
but I'm done with all your little computer games, OK?
我要出去
I want out.
游戏结束!
Game over!
我以为你也喜欢我的
I thought you liked me.
就当我比较传统
Well, call me old-fashioned,
但当你把我变成一串1和0的时候
but you kind of blew it when you turned me
我真没法再有感觉了
into a string of ones and zeros
还把我囚禁在一个虚拟卧室里
and kept me prisoner in a virtual bedsit.
因为这里更好啊!
It's better this way!
我讨厌外面的世界
I hate it out there.
你他妈真是个疯子!
You're a fucking nutter!
行 真行
Just great - perfect.
我好不容易遇到个真心... 噢!
I-I finally meet a girl that I really... Oh!
什么?
What?
没什么
Nothin'.
你只是需要点时间想想清楚
You just need some time to get your head around it.
我已经想过了
I've got me head round it.
对 我想我清楚了
Yeah, I think I have.
呃 我要出去!
Er, I want out!
我知道咱们会很开心的!
I know we can be happy!
你去哪啊?
Where are you going?
你不能把我关在这儿!
You can't keep me in here!
放我走!
Let me go!
你不能这样!
You can't do this!
放我出去!
Let me go!
(费恩)
真的很奇怪 我在街区里走着
It was really weird, because I was walking across the estate
所有人都看我...
and people were looking at me...
还笑我
..and laughing.
已经发生三次了
It's happened three times now.
有个男的盯着我看 满脸笑得巨夸张
This one guy was really staring at me with this big smirk on his face.
噢 真是够了! 操他们
Oh, honestly! Bloody hell.
咱们活在多么奇怪 不可预知的世界里啊
What a strange and unpredictable world we all bloody live in.
到我办公室
My office.
立刻      好
Now.        Yep.
我想给你讲个故事
I want to tell you a story...
好吧
OK.
故事是关于一个男孩 渐渐爱上了
This story involves a young man who developed an affection for another
另一个男孩
young man.
当这个男孩再也无法压抑自己的感情
When the young man could repress his feelings no longer,
他就拍了一段视频...
he made a video...
通过诗歌来表达自己的情感
..expressing his desires via the medium of poetry.
然后用电子邮件发了过去
And the young man sent the video by electronic mail,
或叫e-mail 当时才刚刚有这个东西
or e-mail, as it was to become known.
五分钟后 他的收件箱叮了一声
Five minutes later, there was a ping in his inbox
然后又来一个...
and then another...
接着又一个
and then another.
后来才知道是另一个男孩 他并不感同身受
It transpires that the other young man did not share his feelings...
他觉得那首诗很好笑
He found the poem amusing,
就分享给了所有他认识的人
so he shared it with everyone he knew
那些人又分享给了他们的朋友
who shared it with everyone they knew
就这样一直传下去
and so on and so forth.
当然这个男孩因为这种残忍的拒绝而痛苦不已
And the young man was understandably upset by this cruel rejection,
于是他去质问他心仪的那个男孩
so confronted the object of his desires
在一个没人的地下停车场里
in a deserted underground car park.
他带着满脸的泪水...
And with tears streaming down his face...
一边背诵着那首诗...
..he recited the poem again...
一边把另一个男孩打得血肉模糊
..as he beat the other young man to a bloody pulp.
你明白我的意思没?
Do you see my point?
不太明白
Not really.
或许这个能帮你明白
Perhaps this will help you.
韩国人的混剪
Korean mash-up.
为什么网上会有我拉屎的视频?
Why is there a video of me shitting on the internet?
你在说什么呢?
What d'you mean?
把拉屎这种事传网上?
Making toilet on the internet?
操你丫的 比尔·盖茨! 太过分了 伙计
Damn you, Bill Gates! That's out of order, man.
真不敢相信      是你干的 是不是?
Can't believe it.        It was you, wasn't it?
我能不能...你让我...让我跟你解释一下
Can I just... Let me just say... Let me just say in me defence...
听着 我们大家都犯过大错
Look, we've all made bloody mistakes.
啊!        我操! 杰茜!
Aaaah!      Fucking 'ell! Jess!
你疯了吗?! 杰茜!
What the fuck?! Jess!
操他娘的老天爷啊!
Jesus fucking Christ!
我给你买了披萨
I brought you some pizza.
你以为用几片披萨就能得到我的心么
You think you can just win me over with a few slices of pizza?
可悲!
Pathetic!
我一会儿再来
I'll come back later.
喔 等等...是什么口味的披萨?
Whoa, wait... What kind of pizza is it?
夏威夷口味
Hawaiian.
是你要来这儿跟别人聊咱们的问题
You're the one who wanted to come and talk about our issues,
而且说明一下 那都是因为你内心脆弱
which, for the record, are all in your weak little mind.
但后来我才意识到 这个小组的重要性
But that is before I realised how important this group is.
说真的 你知道吗
Do you know, honestly,
你就像一头在瓷器店里勃起的公牛
you are like a bull with an 'ard-on in a china shop,
真的很荒唐
it's ridiculous.
是不是因为杰茜?
Is this about Jess?
我就是...我不知道该怎么办
I just... I don't know what to do...
你一直做好人 做善事 行为高尚
You try and do the good thing, the right thing, the noble thing,
你是什么都不用担心啊
and what d'you have to show for it?
可我就这么一颗破碎的心和破碎的蛋
A friggin' broken 'eart and a ruptured testicle.
嗯
Hm.
咱们回头见      真棒
I'll see you later.      Brilliant.
我操
Fuck me.
好啊?
All right?
千万保护好你的蛋
Don't ever let your testicles get viciously beaten
别被人用扫帚把毒打
with a wooden broom handle.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
那就好
Do.
那么 我听说了你和费恩那晚在酒吧的事
So I hear you and Finn were in the bar the other night,
当时你的胯部
it was all getting a little bit Lisa King
是不是瞬间莉莎·金了呀?
in the crotch department, wasn't it?
啊?
Eh?
股股流淌的小溪呀
The brook does bubbleth over.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你当然不知道了
Of course you don't know.
淑女是不会明白这种话的
A lady doesn't speak of such matters.
女士您当时还满意么?
Was Madame satisfied?
不 我说真的 我不明白你在说什么
No, really, I don't know what you're talking about.
我在说女士您
I'm talking about Madame.
和费利大人 我想你能在一个
And Master Finlay, I presume he's to be found
满是他自己体液的池子里找到他
in a pool of his own bodily fluids somewhere.
费利是谁?
Who's Finlay?
我的妈 费利就是那个小小的
For God's sake, Finlay is the small,
很善良 跟猴似的那个矮子 你...
well-intentioned monkey-ish little fellow. You...
你是... 你是莉亚 对么?
You are L... You're Leah, aren't you?
噢 我明白了 抱歉
Oh, I get it. I'm sorry.
让你难堪了
You're embarrassed.
非常难为情
And deeply ashamed.
眨三下眼睛我就明白了
Just wink three times and I'll know.
那不是我
It wasn't me.
我想那是我朋友 莉亚
I think it was my friend, Leah.
我想是她对我动了手脚
I think she did something to me.
听着 过不了几天 大家就会去嗨
Look, in a couple of days, everybody is going to be going crazy
新出的某个视频了...
about a new video of a...
什么跳舞小猫 或是...
of a dancing cat, or...
或是大灰熊追逐小矮人!
Or the grizzly bear chasing the dwarf!
那个太经典了 那小腿儿...!
It's a classic, his little legs...!
总之 我的意思是 没人会记得的
Anyway, my point is, no-one remembers it.
显然你就记住了
You obviously remember it.
我觉得你在里面还挺可爱的
I think you looked rather cute, actually,
你的脸都扭成了一团
your face all screwed up and contorted.
你们能不能就他妈的闭上嘴?!
Will you please just shut the fuck up?!
伙计们! 别! 别动手!
Guys! No! Stop!
能不能让我跟你解释一下...
Can I just say, in my defence...
不能 你个傻...!      别!
No, you f...!        Don't!
别再打蛋了!
Not the testicles!
老天爷!
For God's sake!
我想费恩遇到麻烦了
I think Finn's in trouble.
那...这女孩的超能力怎么用?
So...how does this girl's power work?
我不知道 她朋友认为
Well, I don't know. Her mate seems to think
是跟电脑有关的
it's something to do with computers
然后把自己植入别人体内
and friggin' inserting yourself into people.
我也不太明白 但她抓了咱们的小猴子
I don't really understand it, but she has got our little monkey man
而我 不能让人拿他做实验
and I, for one, will not let him be experimented on.
除非她把他打扮成...那种黑猩猩什么的
Unless she's dressing him up, man, like one of them chimps
像茶包广告里那样 我就乐死了
in the PG Tip adverts, then colour me amused.
我能不能就跟你解释一下?
Can I just say, in my defence...?
噢 老天爷!
Oh, my God!
费恩?
Finn?
噢 见鬼!
Oh, shit!
她把他给杀死了!
She's fucking killed him!
费恩 我都没来得及跟你说
Finn, I never had a chance to tell you,
伙计 是我干的!
dude, it was me!
我偷了你外婆的生日钱
I stole the birthday money from your gran,
但我就是借用一下 伙计!
but I were only borrowing it, dude!
我原本要还给你的!
I were going to pay you back!
他有脉搏 他还活着
He's got a pulse, he's still alive.
他不需要知道生日钱的事
He doesn't need to know about the birthday money from his gran,
反正就20块
it was only 20 quid.
他在这里面
He's in here.
她把他存在U盘里
She's got him on a memory stick.
这披萨不错
It's good pizza.
我很高兴你能喜欢
I'm glad you like it.
但这不代表我会留下
This doesn't mean I want to stay here.
这根本都不是真的
It's not even real.
就是一堆1和0
It's just ones and zeros.
这也根本不是真的凤梨罐头 对么?
This isn't even real tinned pineapple, is it?
你最后一次出家门是什么时候?
When was the last time you left your flat?
风暴的那天
The day of the storm.
喔!
Wow!
你真该多出去走走了
You really need to get out more.
真的!
Really!
我以前也会出去
I used to go out.
但渐渐地 我就...
Gradually, I just...
不再出去了
stopped.
网络上的一切都更容易
Everything's easier online.
你可以随便跟人聊天 想讨厌谁都可以
You chat to who you want to chat to, you decide you don't like them,
点一下他们就消失了
one click and they're gone.
永远不用再看见他们
You never have to see 'em again.
他们取笑你
They take the piss.
点一下
Click.
他们耍混蛋 点一下
They act like a dick. Click.
你让自己丢脸 点一下
You embarrass yourself... Click.
明白么 不像外面的世界 这里是你在掌控
See, it's not like being out there, you're in control.
如果这对你来说有用 那很好
If it works for you, great.
可我喜欢外面的世界
'I like it out there.
你就待在这儿点吧 我要走自己的路了
'You stay here and click away, because I'm going to be on my way.'
我们在这儿可以很开心的 我们什么都有了
We can be happy in here, I know we can. We've everything we need.
如果你真的开心
If you're so happy,
你干嘛去互助小组?
then why were you at the support group?
你何必要去 如果你...
Why were you there if...
不想寻求帮助的话?
you didn't want help?
如果这样真的好 你干嘛要去?
If this is so great, why were you there?
你干嘛要去啊?
Why were you there?
因为我孤独!
Because I'm lonely!
你当然会孤独
Of course you're lonely.
你从不离开你的房子
You never leave your flat.
你快劝劝她 费恩
You tell her, Finn.
多愁善感的货
You soft twat.
闭嘴 这多美好
Shut up, this is good.
生命就在你身上白白流走了
'Life is just passing you by.'
真实的生活
Real life.
没错 有时是很糟糕
And yeah, it's shit sometimes.
但有了这些坏事 你才会去感激美好
But you need the shit to appreciate the good things.
就像...
Like...
第一次遇到你喜欢的女孩
the first time you meet a girl you fancy.
那种
That...
羞涩的小颤抖
shy little flutter.
遇到你时我就有那种感觉
I had that when I met you.
在互助小组 我请你去喝酒
At the support group, I asked you for a drink.
那根本都不是我
That wasn't even me.
是你
It was.
那就是你 是你的内在啊
It was you, it was your personality.
而且你也比你朋友漂亮
You're prettier than your friend, anyway.
我...不是说她丑...
I'm... I'm not saying, like, she's a munter...
或是...
or...
反正你比较美
You're prettier.
我们可以试试交往 在真实世界里
We could give it a try, out there.
我喜欢你
I like ya.
你这么说只是想让我放你出去
You're just saying that so I let you go.
你走了就不会再回来了      不是的!
You'll leave and you'll never come back.        No!
如果你也喜欢我 就可以跟我一起留下啊
If you like me, you can stay in here with me.
不 不! 不行!
No, no! No!
费利!
Finlay!
快放了他!
Let him go!
好吧...
Right...
见鬼!
Shit!
我想不出好主意了
I'm all out of brilliant ideas.
你不知道自己错过了什么
You don't know what you're missing.
5英尺4.25英寸的完美之人
Five foot four-and-a-quarter inches of sheer magnificence.
不
No.
不!
No!
快点 快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
快 快 快!
Quick, quick, quick!
放进去了
He's in.
那存储卡呢?      我拿了
Where's the memory stick?        I've got it.
他的手机!
His phone!
好 我们该怎么把费恩从这里弄出来
OK, so how are we going to get Finn out of here
放进他的身体?
and into his body?
这个...
Well...
伙计们 算这位小费利走运
Guys, luckily for young Finlay down here,
我们这儿有个计算机硕士
one of us has a masters degree in computer science.
对 但你又不是真的计算机硕士
Yeah, but you don't actually have a masters degree in computer science,
对吗? 你那文凭是从网上下载打印的
do you? You have a fake certificate that you printed off the internet.
你是因为拉屎的事故意说我吧?
Is this about the shitting?
说真的...老天爷
Because seriously... For fuck's sake.
喂?
Hello?
解决得相当容易啊
That was refreshingly easy.
我感觉咱们越来越上手了 伙计们
I think we're getting better at this stuff, guys.
不如我带他回家 我好好照看他
Why don't I take him home with me and then I can look after him
期间咱们都想一想怎么办?
while we all figure out what we're going to do?
你? 你要照顾他? 你准备怎么照顾?
You? You want to look after him? What are you gonna do with him?
给他洗个澡
Give him a bath.
香薰蜡烛
Scented candles.
每个人都喜欢香薰蜡烛      嗯哼
Everyone likes a scented candle.        Mm-hm.
对 你可以开你的新车送他回去
Yeah, and, um, you can drive him home in your new car,
对么?
can't you?
对
Yeah.
你买新车了?
Have you got a new car?
保险里有我的名字吧? 老天爷哇!
Am I on the insurance? Oh, my God!
咱们弄个房车吧      把存储卡给我
Let's get a caravan.        Give me the memory stick.
我们可以直接开到渡口
We'll get on the ferry,
然后去法国 装一车法棍面包
we'll just go to France, load up with baguettes,
就他妈只管开 伙计们 懂我的意思么?
just fucking drive, guys, you know what I mean?
是她 她下载进入了亚历克斯
It's her. She's downloaded into Alex.
听着 我们可以在一起...
Look, we can be together...
我能让他开心
I can make him happy.
帅酒保 伙计 说真的
Handsome Barman, dude, seriously.
你还在里面不?
Are you in there at all?
啊!      把存储卡给我
Argh!        Gimme the memory stick.
别逼我动手
Don't make me hurt you.
行吧
OK.
老天爷!
Jesus Christ!
快 快 快!
Go, go, go!
喔!
Whoa!
怎么了?        嘘!
What's happening?      Ssh!
他在跟门卫说话呢
He's talking to the caretaker.
所有工种里最高尚的职业
The most noble of all professions.
他一头把他撞翻了! 快闪!
He's fucking head-butted him! Do one!
见鬼!
Shit!
是个死胡同!
It's a dead end!
我想他已经走了
I think he's gone.
那么... 被钉在地板上
Well...nailed to the floor.
头一回啊      对你是头一回
That's a first.        Speak for yourself.
我演校园剧时 受难日重现演砸了
School play, Crucifixion re-enactment gone badly awry.
(费恩)
嗨
Hi.
救命!
Help!
嗨
Hi!
你好?        嗨!
Hello?      Hi!
你是那个电工女孩 我的二重身正找你呢
You're electro girl, me doppelganger's looking for you.
他要跟你谈谈一件毛衣还是什么的
He wants to speak to you about a jumper or something.
你们在干什么?
What are you doing?
我...我知道这要求有点过分
I... I know it's a big ask,
但有没有可能
but is there any chance at all
你能把我们身上的钉子拔了?
that you could pull these nails out of us?
我...正要出去干活 所以...
I'm... on my way to a job, so...
"我正要出去干活"
"I'm on my way to a job."
好心的撒玛利亚人发现耶稣被钉在十字架上
That's what the Good Samaritan said to Jesus when he found him
他跟耶稣是这么说的吗? 你知不知道
nailed to the Cross, but do you know what?
他给他把钉子取了
He friggin' un-nailed him
接着还说"你要不要跟我一起骑上"
and then he said, "Do you want to kip in me stable with that donkey
"这头从伯利恒来的驴?"
"from...Bethlehem?"
然后耶稣就说...你知道他说什么吗? 他说
And Jesus said... Do you know what he said? He went,
"噢 谢了 伙计 你看见那水了么?"
"Oh, cheers, mate. See that water over there?
"我这就把它变成酒"
"I'm gonna turn that into wine.
"和鱼"
"And fish."
你真是熟读圣经呀 对不对?
You really know your Bible, don't you?
我很看重我的信仰
Me faith's very important to me.
我就操了
For fuck's sake.
喔 小心点 小心点 小心点
Whoa, careful, careful, careful.
跟我来
Come with me.
别      你可以的!
Don't.        You can do this!
我会陪着你的
I'll be with you.
来吧
Come on.
别担心 没有什么可害怕的
Don't worry, there's nothing to be scared of.
没人会伤害你的
Nobody's going to hurt you.
放开我的小猴子 你这个疯婆子!
Get off my monkey, you crazy bitch!
放开她!      怎么回事?
Leave her alone!        What happened?
她把自己植入了你的身体 伙计
She has been inserting herself into you, dude,
而且也不是他妈的"我不是基佬"
and not in a fucking "I'm not gay,
"我就只想试一下"那种意思
"I just want to know how it feels" kind of way, neither.
我来处理
I'll handle this.
她已经被处理好了
I think you'll find she's already been handled.
我处理了
By me.
在那里面
In there.
我能不能解释一下... 别 别动手!
Can I just say in my defence... Just don't, just stop!
杰茜! 求你了 你先... 我有些事
Jess! Please, just... There are things
必须告诉你 我就是...
I need to tell you and I just...
你必须听我说
You need to listen.
关于排便的那件事
The business with the defecation,
也许是个失误... 不 根本就是
perhaps that was an error of... No, it was,
因为我的判断失误
it was an error of judgment on my part,
但我的动机 是非常真诚和他妈高尚的
but my motives, they were true and bloody noble.
看着你内脏都快拉出来的样子
Watching you defecate your guts out,
我一点儿都没被吓退
it didn't put me off you at all.
完全没有!
At all!
没有比这更好的方式来检验男人的真心了
There is no greater test of a man's feelings.
我见过了你最他妈丑的样子
I have seen you turn shit-ugly.
可是...
But...
对我来说 你拉得漂亮
But to me, it was shit beautiful.
你真的
You are...
你是个大便美人
You're a beautiful shitter.
怎么了?
What?
等等 等等
Hang on, hang on.
这不是一夜情 对么? 我是说...
It's not just a one-off thing, is it? I mean...
你会做我女朋友吧?
You are going to be my girlfriend, aren't you?
我会做你的女朋友
I'll be your girlfriend.
真的?      真的
Yeah?        Yeah.
我... 抱歉我... 呃...
I... I'm sorry... Um...
上周 你电击我 复苏了我的心脏
Last week, you shocked me and you restarted my heart.
但当时我不是这样 我是个80岁的老头
I didn't look like this, I was an 80-year-old man,
还有老年痴呆症
I had senile dementia.
那个是你?
That was you?
对 我只是...都没机会跟你说声感谢什么的
Yeah, I just... I didn't get chance to say thank you or anything and...
谢谢你
Thank you.
噢! 不 我能不能...?
Ooh! No, can I just...?
我很抱歉打扰你 是关于一件毛衣的事
I'm sorry to bother you, it's about a jumper.
你是不是什么推销毛衣的?
Are you some kind of knitwear salesman?
我看到了未来
I've seen the future.
我想那或许也是你的未来
And I think it might be your future.
那我后来怎么了?
So what happens to me?
我想你变成了超级英雄
I think you become a proper superhero.
这个互助小组都是癌症晚期的年轻人
It's a support group for terminally ill young people.
我是他们的护理人员之一
I'm one of their care assistants.
这他妈的不公平
It's not fucking fair.
你还能怎么样?
What can you do?
对!
Yes!
操你妈的 你个傻逼衰人!
Fuck you, you fucking loser!
拥抱别人...
Holding someone, it...
让我感觉到自己活着
It makes me feel alive.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
我不知道他到底是怎么了
I don't know what's going on with him.
我有东西给你
I've got something for you.
是么?
Yeah?
今天过得不错
This has been a good day.
对 今天过得不错
Yeah, it has been a good day.
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入